The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Knight of the Ribbon,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
Eleventh Episode
The Spirit of Sleep
Sleeping Spirit
Let's play!
Okay!
Let's go!
Your Highness!
Good morning.
Why are you sneaking around?
Today is a day where it's okay to play.
Ah, that's right!
Whoa, I'm flying!
However, you must not get carried away just because you are away from your parents.
You haven't forgotten your promise to your mother, have you?
Rule one!
Keep track of time at the mountain lodge!
And then?
Rule one!
Since I get into fights easily, I must practice not getting angry during this one-week break!
You understand, right?
Alright, I'm going off to play!
Opal!
Good grief...
Help me!
Garigori, where has the Prince gone?
What? It's just Dr. Uranari!
It is not time yet, I tell you!
Time doesn't matter!
He’s a Prince, a young Prince!
The Prince—er, His Highness—
is playing on the hill, but... the time... I mean, the schedule must be kept!
Wow!
Beautiful scenery!
Yeah!
That's the King's chair, right?
Yeah, it's the King's...
I wonder what's about to start?
Your Highness!
Your Highness, please return to the mountain lodge immediately!
No way!
I'm right in the middle of playing!
Don't be ridiculous, go on now!
No, no, I don't want to!
What’s the point of wearing a thing like this!?
The King is ill, so you must deliver the welcoming address in his stead...
Well? Who?
His Highness Plastic.
Plastic?
Huh, Duralumin's kid?
Indeed, that little pest...
If Lord Duralumin hears that, it'll be a disaster!
I mean, did it really take him 8 years to finally graduate from kindergarten?
It took him 8 years to graduate from kindergarten?
Please, keep it down.
Grand Duke Duralumin has arrived!
Oh, Plastic, it doesn't hurt, it doesn't hurt. There, you're fine.
Now, Plastic. Give a proper greeting just like we practiced.
Show them your best side so you don't lose to the likes of Sapphire.
Nylon, you did make him practice, didn't you?
Flawlessly.
Yo, hello.
Prince Sapphire, I would appreciate it if you offered your greeting according to protocol.
Never mind that, never mind that. Plastic, congratulations.
Oh, th-thanks.
Hey now, Plastic, give your greeting.
Turn right.
What kind of practice was that?!
Well, even if you say that...
What's so funny?
Let's skip the greetings and go play.
Forget Duralumin! Plastic, let's go play!
When dining, do this, then that, and then—do you understand?
Drink with your spoon without making a sound.
And then do this, and it goes like this, like this, like this, like this, like this, like this...
Good grief, what a dimwit. Not worth teaching at all.
Straighten up a bit.
Why, you little brat...!
How dare you bite my nose...
Nylon, what were you doing?
Oh, nothing really, I was just astonished by how quick a learner Prince Plastic is.
Oh, is that so? Well then, shall we go to dinner?
A toast to celebrate Prince Plastic's graduation.
Cheers.
Damn it, as if I'd ever let Sapphire sit on that throne!
Sapphire must be a woman.
By law, a woman cannot take the throne.
Once Sapphire is taken care of, the throne will belong to Plastic.
After all, Dad is the King's only brother.
You are more than qualified. Let people laugh if they want—
I will definitely make sure Plastic sits on that throne!
Plastic, where are you going?
I'm going too, Your Highness!
Hey, Plastic, wait up.
Plastic! Come on, let's play, Plastic.
So you like pictures, huh?
Well, that's impossible.
Because this is just a picture, see? You can't take it.
I want to eat dat.
This is called a winter strawberry—a strawberry picked in winter.
But like I said, this is just a picture.
I want to eat dat! I want it!
You want to eat something you can't have?!
What a handful!
I'm sorry, Plastic.
I already said I'm sorry.
I want to eat it!
Well, that's asking for the impossible, Plastic.
It's summer right now. Winter strawberries can only be picked in winter.
I want to eat it!
We have them, we have them!
There are winter strawberries!
What? Are you saying they can be found even in summer?
Yes.
Deep in these woods, there's a field where winter strawberries grow even in summer.
Go pick them.
I've sent the soldiers to fetch them.
However, Grand Duke Duralumin...
Rest assured, I've made sure everyone thinks that the selfish person
demanding winter strawberries in the middle of the night is Prince Sapphire.
Hmm, well done.
It's kind of noisy.
The prize money is mine.
Oh, thank goodness.
Who's making a racket in the middle of the night?
Help!
Are you surprised, you foolish human alliance?
It's a demon!
Foolish humans.
Do you think that will work against the Sandman, the Spirit of Sleep?
Spirit of Sleep.
Anyone staying up late at night is my enemy!
On top of that, you went and trashed the forest!
What kind of punishment should I give you?
Endo!
Yes!
Endo, hand me that!
OK!
Anger potion, crying potion, laughing potion, sleeping potion... Ah, here it is!
Here you go, big brother!
Now, take your punishment!
What!?
I'm an angel, so potions don't work on me.
Fine then, you guys can just go ahead and catch a cold like that!
Serve you right!
Hey, who on earth brought you guys out here in the middle of the night!?
It was Prince Sapphire. Late at night, he suddenly said he wanted to eat winter strawberries.
Prince Sapphire!?
Damn it!
That fool of a prince!
Endo what kind of punishment should we give?
You know, right?
Yes!
Now then, Plastic.
Just a little more patience. Come on, sit on the throne. Let Papa take a look at you.
Yes
Ouch!
Ugh, what an infuriating child!
When I tell you to sit, you sit!
Oh, Papa swears to you.
I will make you King, no matter what!
I will sit you in that seat and place a crown upon your head!
Even if you're a bit lacking, I have the power!
Don't go home early... right on time...
Hey!
You selfish idiot prince!
Lord Sandman has come to punish you!
Wake up!
He's sleeping soundly!
A Sleep Fairy can't go attacking someone who's already asleep!
Alright!
No!
I am the Sleep Fairy, Lord Sandman
I'll make it so you can never sleep again for the rest of your life!
Sleep Fairy?
What's gotten into you all of a sudden?
Don't play dumb!
Because you wanted winter strawberries, the forest is a complete mess!
Stop it!
I won't!
I don't want any winter strawberries!
Then who was it?
The one who wanted them!
You tell me!
You're trying to play dumb!
Grand Duke
Um... the one who wanted winter strawberries was Plastic!
The prince isn't that stupid!
Don't say unnecessary things!
Plastic?
In that case, where is he?!
If you do something terrible to Plastic, I won't forgive you!
Get out of the way! Move it!
Well then, farewell!
You did it!
It's the Wind Fairy!
As if anyone could match Lord Sandman!
Now you've done it!
Tobi-de yo! Hi no sei yo!
Oh no... didn't I promise not to get angry?
Who are you?
Endo!
Hey!
Are you really going to bully someone that young?
I have no intention of bullying them!
This kid tried to hit me out of nowhere! When I dodged, he started throwing a fit!
Good boy, Endo!
I'll make it so you can never sleep again!
Bro, are you gonna go after someone dressed so nicely?
Well, I'll let it slide!
Let's go, Endo!
Alright!
I want to eat winter strawberries...
Here he comes!
Hey you!
You selfish blockhead!
Because of your selfishness, my forest is a complete mess!
What's so funny?!
I'll make it so you can never sleep again!
Plastic... what happened?
Wow, did the winter strawberries arrive?
Who cares about that!
Something's wrong with Plastic!
Strange? Wasn't he already strange to begin with?
Fool!
I mean he’s really become strange now!
Good grief... stupidity can only be cured by death!
Come now, Plastic, close your eyes. Gently, close your eyes...
You're getting sleepy, so very sleepy. It's sleepy-time! Night-night time!
Not only are you an idiot, you’re a total blowhard!
Oh, my Plastic...
Plastic!
How can I help you?
Duralumin, I might be able to cure him!
Wait for me!
Opal!
Your Highness, where are you going?
I'm going to ask the Spirit of Sleep about Plastic!
You must not!
What will you do if the same thing happens to you that happened to Plastic?
I'll be fine!
Besides, don't you feel sorry for Plastic?
Plastic is your enemy!
Oh, that's right!
That hateful son of Duralumin! He is an unforgivable enemy...
trying to usurp your throne! We have no reason to help him!
Idiots!
Sandman!
Sandman! Are you looking for me?!
Where are you?!
Sandman!
Please, I beg you!
What, did you come to get revenge for earlier this evening?
Alright, just you wait!
That's not it!
That's wrong, Sandman!
How's that, pitch black, isn't it!
I can't tell what's going on when it's bright out!
One more time!
What's wrong?
Stop it!
One more time!
Sandman!
Please, you must fix Plastic!
No way!
Please!
I'll apologize for ruining the forest!
You're groveling because you're scared, aren't you?
Coward!
What did you say?!
Oh no! I'm not supposed to fight, am I?
Endo, do that thing to the coward!
Okay, Big Brother!
There we go!
I fell asleep... wait, what?
Stop it!
I told you, no!
Who do you think you are!
Who are you!
Whaddya want?
Insolent, you say?!
Why am I insolent?!
I'm not insolent!
You should just get mad if they do that!
This prank is going way too far!
Ah, that's fairy medicine!
Weakling!
And to think that's supposed to be a prince!
Here is the potion to make them angry!
Now I'm mad!
Now, try this next!
Hey, Sandman!
Sandman's here!
Coward!
You're just like a girl!
Like what?
Sandman!
That's it, now I'm mad!
I'll take you on!
Come on!
Come on, what's wrong?!
Where'd all your energy go?!
Endo, help me!
All right!
Now you've made me angry-!
Like I'd ever tell you, even if you try to intimidate me!
Tell me!
Tell me how to fix Plastic!
No way!
He can just stay like that for the rest of his life!
Please!
Tell me!
If I tell you, will you do as I say?
Yeah!
Then bow down on your hands and knees in front of me and beg!
Bow down and beg?
That's right!
You gotta get on your hands and knees and beg!
What's the matter?
You can't do it, can you?
A prince getting down on his hands and knees to beg!
Please!
Please, tell me!
This is priceless!
A prince just got down on his hands and knees and begged me!
Look, Endo!
And to think he's supposed to be a prince!
Big brother!
That's cowardly!
Sapphire!
I'll teach you a lesson!
You!
You're in a different mood, aren't you!
Going out of your way for someone else's sake!
Sandman!
Plastic!
What is that jar for?
If you try anything funny...!
Shut up!
This is medicine to cure Plastic!
Plastic is cured, thank goodness!
Thank goodness!
Your Highness!
I don't know how to thank you enough!
Shut up!
I didn't do it for the likes of you!
Grand Duke Duralumin!
What do you think of this? This is a
medicine that turns things rock-solid!
You fool!
Are you trying to make him suffer again?!
We pour this on the prince!
On the prince?
That's right!
Grand Duke!
Shedding tears just because he saved us isn't like you at all, Grand Duke!
Let's be cold and calculating here!
Unless we get rid of the prince, Prince Plastic can't take the throne!
That's true enough!
Leave everything to me!
I just had a dream that you saved me!
Don't dream such silly dreams and get a good night's sleep!
Okay!
Now then, I wonder if any kids are staying up late?
Patrol time!
Sleep well...
For me?
You stay like that for a while!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if demons come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP